Eduardo Salguero López

Website: http://edusalguero.com/

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/edusalguero

GitHub: https://github.com/edusalguero

Email: edusalguero@gmail.com

Phone: +34.650074563

Summary

Software Engineer with more than **10 years experience**. In the course of my career I've been in touch with many programming languages like C#, Python or Java even I have focused in **PHP** and **JavaScript**.

I have a great experience in web development and complex architectures; I like to build smart and efficient software, easy to read and that provides added value to its users.

I have been involved in several successful projects like a programmer, **project manager** or **team leader**, taking an active part in design, tests and development.

My interest in **agile development** techniques is increasing every day and I am a Certified Scrum Master. I also spend part of my free time programming and with a continuous training.

I consider myself a curious, responsible person and a team player who is ready to overcome any challenge.

I have a GNU / Linux background even I use Mac OS at home. I like to do some sysadmin tasks because I really believe that knowing the stack where someone works gives you interesting advantages when you have to provide solutions.

Experience

Senior Web developer in A Navalla suiza S.L.. June 2016 - Present

Full stack developer in internal and customer projects in a continuous deployment and delivery environment using Jenkins and GitHub. PHP Backend developer applying SOLID principles using Laravel 5, MySQL and message broker software. Front End developer with ES6, web pack, gulp, grunt and nodejs.

CEO and Software Engineer in *hosting4devs*. June 2014 - Present

Co-founder and software engineer. I take part in the strategy and decision-making process. I am responsible for the management and I am involved in the design, scheduling and execution of the works related with the platform.

Team leader in *Dinahosting S.L.*. September 2009 - Juny 2016

After having worked in several different positions as web developer for the company, I started managing a team of six to ten developers reporting directly to CEO and CTO. We, as a team, defined and built the final product as well as several internal tools for Dinahosting, using mainly PHP.

Senior Developer in *Dinahosting S.L.*. February 2009 - September 2016

In this period I worked mainly in PHP, creating libraries from scratch or extending Zend Framework.

I have also worked in the front end, I built the control panel engine that looked like a desktop environment.

Full Stack Web Developer as freelance. January 2005 - September 2009

I worked as a freelance programmer using PHP mainly. In this period I developed my own MVC and CMS to build websites of my clients. At this time I also did some works with css and html dev.

I managed about ten projects directly with final clients of different and varied profiles like USC or companies in the entertainment industry.

Junior Web Developer in *Dinahosting S.L.*. May 2008 - February 2009

At this role I built Javascript (Vanila JS) features in legacy projects and PHP modules in their own MVC. I also created modules to Wordpress and OsCommerce.

Donnet Developer and PHP Developer in Circulo Gacela S.L. October 2006 - Juny 2008

At the beginning I worked as a remote programmer building modules in the company's framework. At the same time I do sysadmin tasks too.

At the end I built a C# app over a XML PHP API. This software was developed to provide an interface that the clients used to manage their products and services.

Education

Highest level

Degree in Computer Engineering. 2013 - Present

Software Engineering plan

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya.

Completion expected in June 2017.

CISCO Networking Academy Program: CCNA, Wireless & Network Security.

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya.

Technical Engineer in Computer Systems. | 2001 - 2005

Universidade de A Coruna.

Courses and certifications

Certified ScrumMaster® by the *Scrum Alliance*. | September 2015

Course provider by Xabier Quesada of Agilar License 000455894

M101P MongoDB for Developers November 2014

MongoDB, Inc.

License 0c196073f2784dd2ba2a9f259fa68df3

Visual Basic .NET | January 2008 - March 2008

60h - Plan Avanza (MITYC) - PcCarrier.

Languages

Español - Native or bilingual proficiency.

Galego - Native or bilingual proficiency.

English - Professional working proficiency.

Português - Professional working proficiency.

Outstanding projects

Dinahosting: CloudIFlare integration

CloudFlare support to its control panel. The project integrated the demand management and the CloudFlare subscriptions life cycle in the Dinahosting's system.

Dinahosting: Electronic billing & payment solution

An electronic billing and payment solution built with PHP.

Dinahosting: Services control panel - Mobile web version

Mobile version of the services control panel.

Dinahosting: Services control panel - Android and IOS app

Based on the developed mobile web version, the JS application was converted to a native Android application using Phonegap.

Dinahosting: 2013 Control Panel

The new release was not only a design review it was also a complete presentation tier refactoring and a full application tier review.

Dinahosting: Provisioning services system

The provisioning system of products and services allows Dinahosting to manage demand and the products' life cycle.

Dinahosting: Control panel, shop and public web (2009)

In September 2009 Dinahosting launched a new version of their control panel, public web and shop.

Dinahosting: Creowebs site builder

Creowebs is a website builder web-app for everyday people. It was built in PHP and JavaScript.

Frelance: "Colexio de Educadoras e Educadores Sociais de Galicia" Online Portal

The CEESG web was created to bring together in one website all the resources that the Professional Association and its members needed daily

Frelance: "Diccionario Galego de Pedagoxía" research project

The "Dicionario Galego de Pedagoxía" was a project promoted by the "Secretaría Xeral de Política Lingüística" in the "Xunta de Galicia" and managed by the "Universidade de Santiago de Compostela" from the Sepa research group (Facultade de Ciencias da Educación).

Circulo Gacela: ICE Círculo Gacela

The ICE Círculo Gacela (B2C interface) was an app created to connect the customer with business areas in a simple way.